貴様は存在してはならない
You cannot exist!
Don't!
駄目
Be gone, you pitch-black soul.
散れ　漆黒
「犯罪係数　３１」
Crime Coefficient is 31.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象ではありません」
「トリガーをロックします」
Trigger will be locked.
やつのせいで　お前の祖母は死んだ
Your grandmother died
because of him!
Why are you protecting him?!
なぜ　守る？
鹿矛囲は　おそらく　殺害に関与していない
It's unlikely that Kamui had
anything to do with her murder.
正気か？　その男が誘拐させたんだぞ
Are you insane?!
That man had her kidnapped!
確かに　彼なら私の家族の情報を得られた
It's true that he had the means
to obtain information on my family.
でも　それは公安局の人間も同じ
But that applies to the people
at the MWPSB as well.
犯罪者ではなく　同僚を疑うのか
Rather than this criminal,
you suspect your colleagues?
お前はサイコパスが濁ることを恐れ
You're afraid of clouding
your Psycho-Pass,
やつへの感情から目をそらしているだけだ
so you're just trying to turn your back
on your emotions towards him.
憎しみも殺意も消せはしないぞ
You can't eliminate
your hatred or desire to kill.
私は　守らなければいけない大切な命を守れなかった
Even though it is my job,
there were many precious lives I failed to protect.
だけど　法を守ることを絶対に諦めちゃいけないんです
But that doesn't mean
I should give up on protecting the law.
行きましょう
Let's go.
待て　常守朱
Stop! Akane Tsunemori!
ふざけるな…　お前たちに　母さんを
Don't you dare mock me!
I won't let you...
disgrace my mother!
汚させるものか
奪われ続けるなら
If I keep having things taken away from me, I'm gonna lose my mind
Ubaware tsuzukeru nara mou kurutte shimau yo
奪われ続けるなら
もう狂ってしまうよ
This endless "end" will make me stop breathing
Owari no nai "owari" ni boku wa iki wo shinaku natte
終わりの無い「終わり」に僕は息をしなくなって
Enigmatic Feeling
Enigmatic feeling
Why do they have to take things away from me? I'm about to fall apart
Ubawanakya ikenai no? Mou hodokete shimau yo
奪わなきゃいけないの
もうほどけてしまうよ
世界が溶け出して
The world began to melt
Sekai ga tokedashite
もうほどけてしまうよ
世界が溶け出して
God descended to confront and ask me
Kami-sama ga orite kite boku ni tsukitsuketa
神様が降りて来て
僕に突きつけた
"Who are you?"
Who are you?
I freed myself by walking in the divide of this world broken into two
Futatsu ni wakareta sekai ni sotte jibun wo hanatta
２つに分かれた世界に沿って
自分を放った
Is there only one God in such a fine borderline?
Kamihitoe darou kamihitoe darou kyoukaisen kami wa hitori na no?
紙一重だろう　紙一重だろう
境界線　神は１人なの
I'm gonna lose my mind, I'm gonna lose my mind...
Okashiku natte okashiku natte
おかしくなって おかしくなって
Suddenly I'll find myself taking you away
Fui ni kimi wo ubatte shimau no darou
ふいに君を奪ってしまうのだろう
Crazy! Crazy!
Crazy Crazy　完全浮遊体
I'm completely adrift
Kanzen fuyuutai
Crazy Crazy　完全浮遊体
Because my heart can't focus
Pinto no awanai kokoro ni
ピントの合わない心に
Shake me! Shake me!
Shake me Shake me　完全浮遊体
I'm completely adrift
Kanzen fuyuutai
Shake me Shake me　完全浮遊体
I can't even look into the mirror
Kagami sae mo nozokenai
鏡さえも覗けない
Stand your ground!
持ちこたえろ
Stop right there, Shisui!
そこまでだ　酒々井
I can still keep on going... Kamui!
私　まだ　やれるわ…　鹿矛囲
A neuroactive drug?!
She'd go that far for him?
神経刺激薬か　そうまでして…
Very soon... Kamui will
change the world... for us!
あと少しで…　鹿矛囲が世界を…
変えて…　くれる
What made you think
to show me the way?
なぜ　案内する気になった？
I'm doing this in order
to judge you the correct way.
あなたを正しく裁くためよ
You could've gone outside the law
to deal with me.
法の外で　処分することもできた
That's not an option.
そんな選択肢は存在しない
I can tell...
その断定が　あなたをクリアに保っているのが分かりますよ
...that assertion
is what is keeping you clear.
What do you expect Sibyl to do?
君は　シビュラに何を期待しているの？
To bring an end to itself?
シビュラに終わりをもたらすこと？
What is the right judgment in this "ideal" society
where humanity is sacrificed?
人間性を犠牲にした　この理想社会で
正しい裁きとは何でしょう？
I want to see that thing judged!
俺はあれが裁かれるのが見たい
There's another possibility.
別の可能性もある
You, too... I mean, all of you, too,
are aware of it, right?
あなたも…　いえ　あなたたちも気付いているんでしょう？
It's not necessarily true that
you'll get the answer you want.
望んだ答えが得られるとは限らない
Will you still move forward?
それでも　進むの？
The reason we died...
僕たちが死んだ理由…
I looked for the meaning of living
as a dead person and it led me here.
死んだまま　生きる意味を探して
ここにたどりついた
So many have entrusted me
with their hopes.
大勢の願いを託されて…
みんな　癒やしという暴力に苦しんでる
Everyone's suffering from violence
that is referred to as "healing."
I have to save them.
救わなきゃいけないんだ
Sibyl needs to be
brought to justice.
シビュラに報いを　それ以外に救いはない
There's no other way
to save people.
People's anger
makes society clear.
人の怒りが社会をクリアにするのよ
This is a game...
between Sibyl and us!
これはゲームなのさ
俺たちとシビュラの
You could've chosen another way
that didn't mean becoming
違うやり方もあったはず
社会を恨む人たちの思いばかり　背負わずに
the champion of all those
who hold a grudge against society.
That's not an option...
そんな選択肢は存在しない
...even if I had been
able to talk to you sooner.
もっと早く　君と話せていたとしても
To see my lab rat has caused
such a commotion...
私の実験動物が　こんな騒ぎを起こすとはね
Misako Togane...
東金美沙子…
They haven't come to a conclusion yet.
Isn't that right?!
まだ答えは出ていない　そうでしょ？
Akane Tsunemori, your rights
as an Inspector have just been rescinded.
常守朱
あなたの監視官権限はたった今　剥奪されたわ
Now leave, and die
like the dog you are.
ここを出て　野垂れ死ぬといい
I'll go behind those doors
and ask Sibyl if that's their answer.
それがシビュラの答えか　あの扉の向こう側で聞くわ
Kamui?
鹿矛囲？
Putting our lives on the line,
we ask you...
僕たちという存在をかけて　聞こう
Sibyl... can you see our color?
シビュラよ…
僕たちの色が見えるか
As long as I had Mother...
I didn't need anything else.
母さんさえいれば　他に　何もいらなかった
And yet...
なのに…
I have to say goodbye
to you, Sakuya.
お別れよ　朔夜
Huh?
I'm to join the entity
that rules this society.
母さんは　この社会をつかさどるものと一つになるの
This is quite a wonderful thing.
これはとても素晴らしいことなのよ
You'll eventually be led
to the same place, too.
あなたも　いずれ　同じ場所に導かれるわ
Goodbye.
お別れよ
Sakuya?
朔夜？
You belong only to me!
母さんは僕だけのものだ…
And, I got painted black.
そして　俺は黒く染まった
Regardless of whether it is a latent criminal,
an Enforcer or even the Inspectors
潜在犯や執行官のみならず
you work with, you purposely
worsen their Psycho-Pass
担当監視官のサイコパスまで意図的に悪化させ
and then administer
justice upon them.
執行する
Why do you do that?
なぜ　そんなまねを？
Because that's the reason
for my existence.
それが俺の存在理由だからです
My role is to darken souls, even pure ones,
until they become pitch black.
黒いものはより黒く
清いものすら　黒く　黒く　染める
By doing so, you can stay beautiful
and shine bright, mother.
そうすることで　母さんは美しく輝き続ける
I do everything because
of my love for you.
全てはあなたへの愛ゆえ
Mother...
母さん…
Not a target for enforcement action.
Trigger will be locked.
「執行対象ではありません」
「トリガーをロックします」
It's no use.
無駄よ
Sibyl System... If you consider
yourselves the God of Judgment,
シビュラシステムよ
裁きの神を気取るなら　選べる道は一つだ
there is only
one choice before you.
The existence you need to overcome
in order for you to stay as you are
お前たちがお前たちでいるために乗り越えねばならない存在が
is right in front of you!
目の前にいるぞ
Can you judge us?!
裁けるか　僕たちを
Can you question...
our color and your own?!
問えるか　僕とお前の色を
Crime Coefficient is over 300.
「犯罪係数　オーバー３００」
Enforcement mode
is Lethal Eliminator.
「執行モード　リーサル・エリミネーター」
What?!
何？
So this is your color,
huh, Misako Togane?
これがお前の色か　東金美沙子
I won't accept
a change... like this!
認めない　こんな…　変化を
The time for judgment has come.
裁きの時だ
Crime Coefficient is over 300.
「犯罪係数　オーバー３００」
Enforcement mode
is Lethal Eliminator.
「執行モード　リーサル・エリミネーター」
So this is your color, Sibyl.
これがお前の色か　シビュラ
Welcome, Kirito Kamui.
「ようこそ　鹿矛囲桐斗」
Upon deliberation, we decided that
we would acknowledge all of you.
「協議により　私たちはあなたたちを認識することを決断しました」
Also, as Akane Tsunemori suggested,
「また　常守朱の提案どおり
we will institute
a collective Psycho-Pass.
集合的サイコパスを成立させます」
And then, we will discard any elements
that increase our Crime Coefficient.
「その上で　私たちの犯罪係数を上昇させる要因を廃棄します」
We have obtained
a new awareness and perfection now.
「今　私たちは新たな認識と　完全性を獲得しました」
This is our way of evolving.
「これが　私たちの進化の形です」
Target's Threat Judgment
has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が　更新されました」
Crime Coefficient is 0.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「犯罪係数　ゼロ」
「執行対象ではありません」
Trigger will be locked.
「トリガーをロックします」
This is the answer.
これが答えよ　鹿矛囲桐斗
Kirito Kamui...
You are under arrest.
あなたを逮捕します
Go!
行け
Surrender!
It's over now!
投降しろ　もう終わりだ
Stop it! Shisui!
もうよせ　酒々井
No... It's not over yet!
いいえ…　まだよ…
I'll be the path for Kamui.
私が　鹿矛囲の道になる…
Those bombs that Division 3
placed with care...
三係が　丁寧に設置してくれた爆弾よ
You're the ones
who'll meet your end here!
あなたたちの方こそ　ここで終わるの
Don't!
よせ
ありがとう　鹿矛囲
Thank you... Kamui...
Sorry I was late.
遅くなりました
Indeed.
まったくだ
But you made it
in time this time.
今回は間に合ったな
Yes.
はい
It's okay.
She's still alive.
大丈夫　生きてる
Aoyanagi, we took back
your junior Inspector.
お前の後輩を取り戻したぞ
青柳
We're in the middle
of an operation.
今は作戦行動中です
Shut up and do as I say!
黙って従え
You're an Inspector.
You should know my location!
監視官なら位置は分かるだろ？
Come right away!
すぐに来い
Mother...
母さん…
このままじゃいけない…
Things can't stay like this.
It's all his fault...
His fault...
全て　あいつが悪いんだ
あいつが…
Under Chief's orders, I'm headed out
to take care of a different task.
局長の指示で　別任務に向かいます
You Enforcers, follow
Inspector Domoto's instructions!
あなたたちは堂本監視官に従って
別任務？
A different task? Hey!
おい
Crime Coefficient is over 400.
「犯罪係数　４００」
Enforcement mode
is Lethal Eliminator.
「執行モード　リーサル・エリミネーター」
What color am I now?
僕は　今　何色かな
Inspector Tsunemori, it is recommended
that you administer justice immediately.
「常守監視官　速やかな執行を推奨します」
Do not resist
and hand over that Dominator.
抵抗せず　ドミネーターを渡しなさい
感じるよ
I can feel it.
Even some in that thing are happy
to have their own color back.
あれの中にも
自分の色を取り戻せて喜んでるものたちがいる
Happy?
喜ぶ？
Why aren't you pointing
the Dominator at Sibyl?
君こそ　なぜシビュラにドミネーターを向けない？
If it's a collective entity,
集合的であるならば
ドミネーターを向ける者も　また　その一部になる
the one who's holding
the Dominator becomes a part of it.
If someone else points it at that thing,
it may show a different color.
別の誰かが向ければ
あれは違う色になるかもしれない
You...
あなたは…
There's no longer
any going back for Sibyl.
シビュラは　もう　後戻りできない
When a true judge
appears someday,
いつか本当の裁き手が現れたとき
no matter how many brains it removes,
its Crime Coefficient may remain high.
あそこにいる脳が最後の一つになっても
犯罪係数は下がらないままかもしれない
Don't tell me...
That was your plan from the start?
まさか　最初から　そのつもりで…
Administer justice,
Inspector Tsunemori.
「執行を　常守監視官」
It's possible that
judge might be
もしかすると　その裁き手は
the person standing
in front of me right now.
今　僕の目の前に　いる人かもしれない
Stop it.
やめて…
I'm not you! I don't simply take
the wishes of others upon myself.
私は　あなたじゃない
誰彼構わず　人の願いを受け入れたりしない
If only you had chosen a way that
didn't lead to anyone getting hurt...
せめて血を流さない道を選んでいれば
That's not an option.
そんな選択肢は　存在しないんだ
そこから出ろ　冒涜者ども
Get out of there!
Desecrators!
やめなさい
Stop it!
I like the look in your eyes.
いい目だ
You know, don't you?
That I was the one who killed Aoi Tsunemori.
気付いているだろう？
常守葵を殺したのは　この俺だと
She was just a shriveled old woman,
but she put up a good fight.
ひからびた老人のくせに　しぶとくってな
あーちゃん　あーちゃんと　呼び続けていたぞ
She kept calling your name,
"Akane... Akane..."
There's another option.
You're aware of it too, aren't you?
別の可能性もある　君も気付いているだろう？
The spirit of the law...
That's what you want to respect.
君が願う　法の精神
If that can become the scales of justice
that weigh all of society equally,
もし　それが　社会という存在に等しく正義のてんびんとなるなら
that spirit itself may change
that monster there into a real god someday.
いつか　その精神こそが　あそこにいる怪物を
本当の神様に変えるかもしれない
This isn't possible!
あり得ない…
There's no way you can be
purer than my mother!
お前などが　母さんよりも清らかなものか
なぜだ…
Why...
Why isn't your soul
turning black?!
なぜ染まらない…
東金朔夜
Sakuya Togane.
You're under arrest
for acts of rebellion
反逆行為　ならびに　常守葵の殺害容疑で
as well as on suspicion
of murdering Aoi Tsunemori.
あなたを逮捕します
「常守朱監視官　あなたの提案により
Inspector Akane Tsunemori,
it is gratifying that following your suggestion,
私たちの中で　議論され続けてきた問題が
we solved the problems we have been
discussing amongst us all this time.
解決を迎えたのは　喜ばしいことです」
However, with our current
processing ability,
「ただし　今の処理能力では
we cannot institute a collective Psycho-Pass
for all of society as of yet.
まだ　社会全体の集合的サイコパスは　成立し得ない」
In order for that day to come,
we recommend you continue
「その日のために　今後も　社会に貢献し
to contribute to society
and live a healthy life.
健やかに生きることを推奨します」
来たか…
So you came...
Crime Coefficient is 899.
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
「犯罪係数　８９９」
「執行モード　リーサル・エリミネーター」
A child of Sibyl? Don't make me laugh.
You're pitch black.
何がシビュラの子よ…　真っ黒
Mother...
母さん…
You and I are both
slaves to Sibyl after all.
あなたも　俺も　結局　シビュラの奴隷でしたね
I can't forgive myself
for obeying you.
あなたに従った　自分が許せない
I can't remain clear
unless I do this.
こうしなきゃ　私がクリアじゃなくなるの
So she's your new slave, huh?
この娘が　新しい奴隷というわけですか
Do your best and live
only to keep Sibyl beautiful.
せいぜい　シビュラを　美しく保つためだけに
生きて…
Someone who clouds
my Psycho-Pass should disappear!
私を濁らせる人間なんて　消えればいい
I won't go any farther than this.
私　ここから先へは進みません…
秘密は守ります
I'll keep the secret.
No, I'll forget about everything!
いえ　全部忘れます
I don't know anything!
何も知りません
I trust Sibyl!
I love this society!
私　シビュラを信じます…
私　この社会が大好きですから
Akane Tsunemori!
常守朱
I've been informed that
命令違反により　権限剥奪との通達を受けている
your rights as an Inspector
are rescinded for disobeying orders!
Do not resist and put
your hands behind your...!
抵抗せず　両手を頭の後ろに…
Don't!
よせ　やめろ
Stop it!
H-Her rights are reinstated.
け…権限　戻ってる
What color am I now?
私は　今　何色ですか
As clear as crystal...
奇麗なもんだ
I located the escaped
Enforcer Sakuya Togane.
脱走した東金朔夜執行官を発見
He died before I administered justice.
That concludes my report.
執行前に死亡　報告は以上です
Well... thanks for
accompanying me back here.
さてと　見送り　ご苦労さん
Your Psycho-Pass is on its way to recovery.
You don't have to...
先生のサイコパスは回復傾向にあります
戻る必要は…
I know why it's recovering.
回復の理由は分かってる
Being dependent doesn't
quite suit me, so...
依存するのは　性に合わないんでね
また来ます
I'll come see you again!
Looking forward to it.
楽しみにしてるよ
A man who clouds the Psycho-Pass
of those he touches, huh?
触れたら　サイコパスが濁る男か…
Once he leaves, I feel like
I missed my chance.
いないとなると　ちょっと惜しい気もするのよね
According to Kuwashima,
it turned out that it was Sakuya Togane
桒島の証言から
常守監視官の親族の情報を流したのは東金朔夜と判明
who leaked the information
on Inspector Tsunemori's grandmother.
However, now we'll never find out
where he obtained that information.
しかし　彼が　どこで情報を手に入れたか
今となっては　分からない
残念です
That's unfortunate.
Whoever that person is,
I'll never forgive them.
誰であれ　許す気はないわ
Same here.
同感です
今回の件で　システムに多くの空席が生まれた
After this recent series of crimes,
we have many vacancies in the system.
To tell you the truth, some of us
suggested that we bring you in.
実は　君を迎え入れては　という案が出ている
If you wish for change,
why don't you try instituting change from inside?
変革を望むなら　内側から試みてはどうだ？
そこまで私に興味はないくせに
I know you're not that interested in me.
Are you trying to provoke me?
挑発？
Are you turning it down?
断る　ということかね？
For now, yes. When the time comes
that you yourselves decide to be rid of you,
今はね
あなたたち自身が　廃棄を選択するときが来たら
I'll go to hell with you.
一緒に地獄へ行ってあげる
A collective Psycho-Pass...
集合的サイコパス
In the not-so-distant future,
there will be a society
遠くない将来　集団が基準となる社会が訪れる
where groups
become the standard.
The possibility that even if each individual is clear,
the group isn't...
個人としてクリアでも
集団としてクリアではない可能性
その疑心暗鬼が混乱を招き
The doubts and fears that arise
from that may lead to disarray.
かつてない魔女狩り社会が訪れ
Society may engage
in an unprecedented witch-hunt...
その結果…
As a result... judgments
may turn into massacres.
裁きは大量虐殺へと変貌を遂げるかもしれない
And it's you who opened the door.
その扉を開いたのは　君だ
I'm not that pessimistic.
私は　そこまで悲観しない
What comes of this may be righteous
law and order, and peace and freedom.
訪れるのは正しい法と秩序　平和と自由かもしれない
Such optimism.
That's just like you.
君らしい楽観だ
楽観だろうと　選ばなければ実現しない
Maybe it's optimistic,
but we can't know unless we try.
It is not society that
determines people's futures.
社会が　人の未来を選ぶんじゃないわ
It is people who determine
society's future.
人が社会の未来を選ぶの
That's what I believe.
私は　そう信じてる
All is calm, all is bright
All is calm All is bright
A whispering fallen angel
Sasayaku tenshi wa ochite
囁く天使は堕ちて
Gently devours you, body and soul
Yasashiku hamu wa anata no subete o
優しく食むわ　あなたの全てを
It's my guilty
You notice me
Kidzuku
気づく　目を見開いてる
With your eyes wide open,
Me o mihiraiteru
A faint blue as lifeless as concrete
Honoaoi konkuriito
仄青い混凝土
In a cold tone,
Tsumetaku watashi o
冷たく私を
Call my name and give me a kiss
And then hold me in the arms of the empty shell that is your body
Soshite dakishimete anata no inai sono karada de
そして抱きしめて
あなたのいないその体で
That soul that you've cast out
Hakidashita sono inochi wa
吐き出しその生命は
Has not yet completely vanished
Mada katachi o nokoshiteiru wa
まだ形を残しているわ　紅く
I glimpse a vivid red eternity
Akaku azayaka na eien ga miete
鮮やかな永遠が見えて
It starts singing right next to me
Tonari de sore wa utaidasu
隣でそれは歌いだすわ
What was I born for
Come on, love me
Nee watashi o aishite
ねえ　私を愛して
Because I won't let you go
Hanasanai kara
離さないから
Hello my name is
A world where humans' state of mind
and the tendency of their personalities can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed, these measured numbers used to judge people's souls
are commonly called 'Psycho-Pass.'
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations
that appear in the show are fictitious,
and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.